<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>evilsaloon</title>
    <link href="https://evilsaloon.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://evilsaloon.com" />
    <updated>2022-07-30T19:48:03-04:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Maximilian Vidavsky</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://evilsaloon.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Is There Finance After Sanctions?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Maximilian Vidavsky</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://evilsaloon.com/is-there-finance-after-sanctions/"/>
        <id>https://evilsaloon.com/is-there-finance-after-sanctions/</id>
        <media:content url="https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/3/antuan-2.PNG" medium="image" />
            <category term="sanctions"/>
            <category term="russia"/>
            <category term="finance"/>
            <category term="article"/>

        <updated>2022-07-30T19:48:03-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/3/antuan-2.PNG" alt="" />
                    It’s been 5 months since Russia invaded Ukraine, and most Russians are still reeling from the economic sanctions imposed on the nation. From the voluntary “operation suspension” by the likes of Visa and Mastercard to the removal of several Russian banks from the SWIFT network,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/3/antuan-2.PNG" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>It’s been 5 months since Russia invaded Ukraine, and most Russians are still reeling from the economic sanctions imposed on the nation. From the voluntary “operation suspension” by the likes of Visa and Mastercard to the removal of several Russian banks from the SWIFT network, private and public institutions alike have swiftly acted to punish the nation’s government for its actions, as well as the rest of the Russian populace. This article will explore how both the average consumer and the financial market have adapted to these changes.</p>
<h2>Foreword</h2>
<p>It is extremely important for me to stress that this article isn’t political. There is a plethora of people infinitely more qualified than me to dissect the political nature of the Ukraine-Russia regional conflict. However, having lived in Russia for most of my life, I believe that I am in the unique position to pull back the “Financial Iron Curtain”, to bring back firsthand accounts about how the average (non-oligarch) Russian is living with these sanctions.</p>
<p>I also must warn potential readers that most of this article is unsourced. I am the primary source for a lot of this information, simply because this situation is so niche. While I tried my best to make sure all the information is accurate and up-to-date, in the post-sanction financial world, so many of these things change so quickly that a lot of information might be out of date within a matter of months, weeks, or even days. Take what I say with a grain of salt.</p>
<h2>The Financial Iron Curtain</h2>
<p>When Visa and Mastercard announced that they were pulling out of Russia, the entire country was taken by surprise. In a world where borders matter less and less, especially in the realm of finance, most people relied on Russian banks’ generous “no foreign transaction fee” policy to conduct business abroad. However, immediately after the sanctions were enacted, Russians living abroad and foreigners living in the country were suddenly cut off from the easiest way to access their funds.</p>
<p>At the same time, a vast number of companies pulled out of the country (over 1000 according to <a href="https://som.yale.edu/story/2022/over-1000-companies-have-curtailed-operations-russia-some-remain" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Yale</a>), severely crippling the average Russian’s quality of life. While I’m sure most people can live without Spotify or YouTube Premium, there is no denying the impact of payments for more essential services being unable to go through. If you were renting a server from AWS or Google Cloud, sitting the SAT or IELTS, buying airplane tickets or booking hotels, ordering spare parts for your car from Europe, or doing anything remotely related to cross-border commerce and travel, you now had to scramble to find a way to pay for services rendered without having them inexplicably taken away.</p>
<p>There is, however, a large problem: the average Russian citizen does not have a bank account abroad. According to Russia’s Federal Tax <a href="https://tass.ru/ekonomika/10459951" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Service</a>, only 700 thousand citizens have bank accounts abroad. To put this number into further perspective, only 543 thousand Russians have at least a second citizenship, according to Russia's Ministry on Internal <a href="https://tass.ru/obschestvo/7458917" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Affairs</a>. Even if we assume that 2/3 of people with said luxuries don’t report them to the government, that’s still a measly 1.45% of the country with foreign bank accounts. It is impossible to accurately count these numbers, but even with the most generous assumptions, just shy of 99% percent of the country is currently behind the financial iron curtain, unable to make payments abroad.</p>
<h2>Card Tourism</h2>
<p>Now that we know the scale of the problem, it’s not surprising that “card tourism” is becoming more and more popular in Russia. Russia is part of the CIS, an EU-like trading and economic bloc consisting of most post-Soviet states. Many CIS member nations have visa-free agreements with Russia, allowing Russian citizens to stay for 90 days without filing for a visa. Because of this, and the fact that only Russia and Belarus have been affected by the latest round of sanctions, a new sanction-evading loophole has appeared: a Russian citizen can travel to a CIS member state for a week and open a bank account there, at a bank not sanctioned by the West. This is called "card tourism".</p>
<p>Many CIS banks are taking advantage of the situation by imposing high account maintenance fees and charging large sums of money for express debit card issuance. One such bank is UniCredit Bank in Armenia. According to a relative who has travelled to Armenia to open an account there in March, here’s how the fees for nonresidents stack up:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“50k dram [~123 USD] yearly maintenance, 125k dram [~306 USD] for express card issuance (they issued a card within half a day). If you can wait 5 days, they issue the card for free.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>All in all, the average person would have to pay about 1000 USD, including flights, hotels, and all other associated fees and taxes. To illustrate why this is unfeasible for most people, we can look to the US. The average US resident is better off than the average Russian resident in almost every way: life expectancy, GDP per capita, etc. Despite all this, 56% of Americans cannot afford to cover a surprise $1000 expense, according to <a href="https://www.bankrate.com/banking/savings/financial-security-january-2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bankrate</a>. If the average American can't afford to engage in card tourism, how is the average Russian expected to do the same?</p>
<p>The answer is simple. They aren't.</p>
<h2>SWIFT Shenanigans</h2>
<p>Opening a bank account abroad, however, is just the first half of the problem. In order to use a foreign account, there needs to be a way to it to be funded. Russia has its own P2P fast payments system - <a href="https://sbp.nspk.ru/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SBP</a> - but that system works only in rubles and doesn't work outside of the country. Russian wire transfers don't work outside of the country, either. That leaves three ways to transfer money out of the country:</p>
<ol>
<li>Withdrawing rubles, exchanging them for an arbitrary currency (in the case of Armenia, Armenian drams) and depositing them abroad in person. This is obviously impractical to do, even for the possible largest amounts.</li>
<li>Using certain banks' internal money exchange systems or external networks like Unistream and KoronaPay (popular Western networks like MoneyGram, Western Union and the like have all pulled out of the country). In this case, you will lose money thrice:
<ol style="list-style-type: lower-roman;">
<li>Exchanging RUB to an arbitrary currency using a poor exchange rate.</li>
<li>Commissions to the bank/payment network for using their services.</li>
<li>Exchanging the arbitrary currency back to USD at an even poorer exchange rate.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Using a network specifically designed to alleviate this pain: SWIFT.</li>
</ol>
<p>However, out of Russia's top 10 consumer-oriented banks, only 3 haven't been disconnected from the SWIFT network: Gazprombank, Raiffeisen, and Rosbank. Russia's most popular bank according to <a href="https://www.banki.ru/banks/ratings" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">banki.ru</a>, Sberbank, was one of the first to be sanctioned, which means that a very sizable portion of Russians cannot even begin to transfer money out of the country.</p>
<p>Assuming they find a bank enough with a low enough commission rates, using a resource like <a href="https://xn--80aqfjcw2bze.net/table/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">санкциям.net</a>, there is still the problem that Western banks are scrutinizing every Russian transfer. Take for example Gazprombank. According to data crowdsourcing website <a href="https://ohmyswift.ru/bank/%D0%93%D0%90%D0%97%D0%9F%D0%A0%D0%9E%D0%9C%D0%91%D0%90%D0%9D%D0%9A%20(%D0%93%D0%9F%D0%91)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ohmyswift.ru</a>, most recent transfers have either refunded or didn't arrive at the recipient's account yet. There is also a note at the top of the page:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"24.07.2022 There is unofficial information about problems with [Gazprombank's] dollar correspondent bank since July 20. Transfers could take longer than a month."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Correspondent banks are intermediaries in the SWIFT system. Rather than having payment agreements with every single bank everywhere around the world, most banks use a correspondent bank that has agreements with both the sender and recipient bank when sending an international wire transfer. This keeps costs reasonably down for everyone in the ecosystem.</p>
<p>However, this means that your money could pass through two or more intermediary banks that can halt or refund your transfer as they please. It doesn't matter if you're transferring money to Asia or Africa, if a single European or American correspondent bank handles money originating from Russia, they will ask for additional documentation, or have the option to refund your transfer outright.</p>
<p>This is an issue because regular account holders have no relationship with correspondent banks, since they work on a B2B level directly with regular banks. This means that while they are incentivized to make sure the payment goes through via their commission, they have no legal obligation to make it go though, and can decline or delay your payment as they see fit.</p>
<p>Looking back at OhMySwift, we can see that transfers take 1-22 days to complete, with most recent ones being refunded or "hanging" (still being processed). This unreliability plagues all new SWIFT transactions out of Russia. Because of the way the network works, there is no way to ask your bank to avoid Western correspondent banks, meaning that every outgoing Russian international wire from now on is essentially a leap of faith.</p>
<h2>Vaguely Extortion</h2>
<p>Just like in the banking world, tough times have created a ripe environment for intermediaries to take advantage of the situation. One such example can be found on Avito: Russia's answer to eBay and Craigslist. Freelancers and average people alike have found a home on the website, where you can do anything from sell a couch to offer your professional services. Recently, however, sellers with foreign bank accounts have realized their unique position and have begun offering their services on the website.</p>
<p>Here's how a typical "helping pay with a card abroad" (a popular search term for this type of activity of Avito) transaction goes through:</p>
<ol>
<li>The client finds a seller using Avito's search and contacts them with the price of the item or the subscription they want.</li>
<li>The seller gets back to the client with the price in rubles, usually with some sort of markup for their services.</li>
<li>The client pays upfront and then receives either the item they pay for or a refund if the transaction is unsuccessful.</li>
</ol>
<p>Because the exchange rate from rubles to whatever foreign currency is public knowledge, sellers cannot make money like most banks do via quoting an inflated exchange rate. Instead, they use whichever bank's exchange rate is the highest at the time of the transaction to convert from an arbitrary foreign currency to rubles, and then add on their commission at the end.</p>
<p>Typically, market forces would work to lower these commission rates, and, in the banking world, this is typically the case. Most Russian banks use the mid-market exchange rate for foreign transactions, and usually waive foreign transaction fees on debit/credit cards entirely. However, because the vacuum left by Visa and Mastercard's exit from the market is so extreme, sellers can get away with 10-25% commission rates and high (500-1000 RUB or 8-16 USD) transaction minimums.</p>
<p>Avito also has a rating system that clients can use to leave feedback, but systems like this can easily be abused. It is not impossible for a scammer to create a new profile, buy a bunch of fake 5-star reviews, and then scam a big fish that comes along. Most sellers require payment upfront to execute the transaction (this is a common Russian business practice, since, according to proverb, "Nothing strengthens faith in a person like advance payment"), and a financially unsavvy buyer could easily fall for a scam of this sort.</p>
<p>There is also the matter that this financial activity is strictly in the legal grey zone. Since sellers are regular individuals paid in rubles via P2P payment systems in Russia and execute their transactions using their own personal cards tied to foreign bank accounts, there is no practical way for sellers to execute KYC checks on their customers. There is also no practical way for tax agencies on either side of the financial iron curtain to tax these transactions, since they are cross-border, cross-jurisdiction, and are often not executed via traditional means.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/3/antuan.PNG" alt="One such Avito seller, with over one hundred 5 star reviews." width="1702" height="873" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/3/responsive/antuan-xs.PNG 300w ,https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/3/responsive/antuan-sm.PNG 480w ,https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/3/responsive/antuan-md.PNG 768w ,https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/3/responsive/antuan-lg.PNG 1024w ,https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/3/responsive/antuan-xl.PNG 1360w ,https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/3/responsive/antuan-2xl.PNG 1600w"><figcaption>One such Avito seller, with over one hundred 5 star reviews.</figcaption></figure>
<p>Since the SWIFT network is extremely unreliable when it comes to moving money out of the country, most sellers use cryptocurrency instead of wire transfers. This makes it even harder for tax agencies to track, especially if sellers use P2P exchanges. While the break-even margin for cryptocurrency transfers is anywhere from 0.5-7% depending on the time of day and volatility of the markets (speaking from personal experience), crypto payments move incredibly fast, taking anywhere from 10 minutes to one hour to move money out of Russia and into the West. This allows sellers to have empty bank accounts at both the start and end of the business day, lowering the effective risk of bank account closures.</p>
<p>Because so much of the seller's business is dependent on moving money out of the country cheaply and quickly, these individuals operate at a speed and scale unheard of in the financial world. They utilize every mean at their disposal to cut costs; means that are inaccessible to businesses too reliant on reporting every transaction for taxation and regulatory purposes. Private companies simply cannot fill this gap because the regulatory risk is too high (banks will not want to work with a business whose main goal is to tip-toe the line around international sanctions, and the workflow required to keep these transactions legal would stifle any attempt to get into the market).</p>
<p>This means that the core of this business is made up of a few dozen individuals willing to take the risk for making these types of transactions, attracted only by profit and not by the willingness to help their fellow citizens. Their actions could vaguely be classified as extortion - since, for most people, there is simply no other alternative.</p>
<h2>Dollar Drain?</h2>
<p>Despite the crazy lengths people are willing to go in order to pay for things abroad, there is also the problem of moving money out of the country. While individuals can use cryptocurrency to move money around, most people aren't proficient enough with these means, and prefer to use the traditional tools at their disposal.</p>
<p>In order to avoid immediate inflation and a deficit of foreign currency in the nation, the Central Bank of Russia barred nonresidents and companies from "unfriendly nations" from transferring money out of the country, with foreign banks scrambling to rehire staff after they realized Russia would not let them pull out so easily, according to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/exclusive-citi-raiffeisen-other-foreign-banks-seek-staff-russia-they-struggle-2022-07-21/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reuters</a>. Regular people could only transfer $5000 a month abroad at the start of the way, but this limit was later raised to $150 000, and now $1 million, according to Russian news agency <a href="https://www.vedomosti.ru/finance/news/2022/06/30/929294-tsb-limit-perevoda" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Vedomosti</a>.</p>
<p>While the Central Bank says that this limit has been raised due to "a stable position on the internal foreign currency market", it's unclear whether this is actually the case, or if the bank is trying to diminish an already significant dollar drain with a sheer show of confidence.</p>
<p>Despite the Central Bank's measures to inspire confidence, there is now essentially a grey market for foreign hard currency in Moscow. Only people who have had foreign currency accounts since the 8th of March can withdraw hard cash from bank offices, according to Russian news agency <a href="https://www.rbc.ru/finances/09/03/2022/622845f09a79474465e912af" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RBK</a>, with banks disabling ATM withdrawals. At that time, most big banks didn't have any foreign currency left in their ATM machines. Because of this, while the official exchange rate is set pretty low, most people cannot buy currency and withdraw it at that low rate from a bank, forcing them to buy currency at a markup from a third party.</p>
<p>We can also speculate why SWIFT transfers from Russia take so long. It might not entirely be the fault of Western partners, but also of Russian banks trying to avoid total devaluation of their foreign currency reserves. Several anecdotal cases have been reported of Russian banks claiming to have sent funds, but neither the correspondent or recipient bank having ever received them.</p>
<p>All this uncertainty around traditional banking has pushed people to explore cryptocurrency and alternative networks. It is unclear whether banks are lying in order to save their assets or at the behest of the Central Bank or, indeed, if they are even lying at all. One thing is for certain - very shady things are happening with foreign currency in Russia.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>We will never know if Visa and Mastercard's decision to pull out of Russia was self-imposed, fearing violating AML/sanctions policies, or, perhaps, forced by the US government. At the end of the day, there is something to be said about how two US-based companies control the vast majority of the world's consumer transactions.</p>
<p>While allowing two players to consolidate the card payment industry has allowed for financial globalization at an unprecedented scale, we magically seemed to forget the main pitfall of such centralization: we do not control our own money.</p>
<p>Your bank can close your account, your credit card issuer can pull out of the country, your government can become sanctioned... Your hard-earned currency can become a virtual paperweight with the click of a button and the issuance of a single press release.</p>
<p>This is the reality on the ground in Russia. The average citizen has no recourse and no way out. Shady intermediaries with the means to skirt sanctions will offer their services at a markup regardless of the legality. Some people got around the restrictions, others are still stuck without a working card.</p>
<p>I personally wouldn't inflict a punishment like this upon my worst enemy.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>BlueStacks and Charles Proxy: A Better Love Story</title>
        <author>
            <name>Maximilian Vidavsky</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://evilsaloon.com/bluestacks-and-charles-proxy/"/>
        <id>https://evilsaloon.com/bluestacks-and-charles-proxy/</id>
        <media:content url="https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/4/bst1-2.PNG" medium="image" />
            <category term="tutorial"/>
            <category term="charles"/>
            <category term="bluestacks"/>
            <category term="android proxy"/>

        <updated>2022-07-30T18:16:37-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/4/bst1-2.PNG" alt="" />
                    Recently, I came across a problem: my trusty rooted Android 4 phone couldn't install an app whose API I wanted to reverse engineer, because the app was targeting Android versions 7 and above. Instead of buying a newer phone for my needs, I started looking&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/4/bst1-2.PNG" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>Recently, I came across a problem: my trusty rooted Android 4 phone couldn't install an app whose API I wanted to reverse engineer, because the app was targeting Android versions 7 and above. Instead of buying a newer phone for my needs, I started looking towards emulators.</p>
<p>The first article I came across was from Mark Dappollone on <a href="https://mdapp.medium.com/the-android-emulator-and-charles-proxy-a-love-story-595c23484e02" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Medium</a>, but it was published back in 2017 and didn't address my main concern: installing Android Studio just to use its emulator is a massive waste of time and hard drive space. Android Studio is completely unintuitive, and the emulator does not work on my machine at all.</p>
<p>Not only that, but it's meant for developers who can add their own SSL certificates into apps, which is impractical for reverse engineering, when we usually don't have access to the source code. Instead, I turned to an emulator I had used before, BlueStacks. This article will teach you how to root the BlueStacks emulator and use it to proxy calls.</p>
<h2>Step 1 - Installation</h2>
<p>Of course, you will need to install <a href="https://www.charlesproxy.com/download/latest-release/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Charles</a> first. For the emulator, I recommend <a href="https://www.bluestacks.com/download" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">downloading</a> the latest 64-bit version of BlueStacks 5, since it supports Hyper-V. Once downloaded and installed, launch the application once and let the emulator fully load.</p>
<p>Once loaded, close the emulator and download the latest version of <a href="https://bstweaker.tk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">BlueStacks Tweaker</a>. This nifty program will allow us to root the emulator, as well as install Xposed. The latest beta works with the latest version of BlueStacks 5 (5.9).</p>
<h2>Step 2 - Root + Xposed</h2>
<p>Open BlueStacks Tweaker and navigate to the "Root" tab. Make sure the emulator is closed and press "Unlock". This will unlock the emulator for rooting. Once that is done, press the "Play" button next to your emulator and wait for the emulator to load. Make sure you have Android Nougat (7.1), because BlueStacks Tweaker doesn't support the Android Pie beta yet.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/4//bst1.PNG" alt="" width="1023" height="559" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/4//responsive/bst1-xs.PNG 300w ,https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/4//responsive/bst1-sm.PNG 480w ,https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/4//responsive/bst1-md.PNG 768w ,https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/4//responsive/bst1-lg.PNG 1024w ,https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/4//responsive/bst1-xl.PNG 1360w ,https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/4//responsive/bst1-2xl.PNG 1600w"></figure>
<p>Once the emulator has loaded, press "Patch", then "Install SuperSu", then "Update Su binary". This will close the instance, so don't be surprised. Launch it again, and under the Xposed tab, press "Patch", "Install", and then "Flash". Restart the instance, and then open Xposed. It should say "Xposed Framework version 89 is active." and display a green checkmark. This means we can move onto step 3.</p>
<h2>Step 3 - Root Certificate + Proxy</h2>
<p>Now that our "device" is rooted and Xposed, we can start by setting the proxy. Kudos to u/ProgramTechie on Reddit for figuring out the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/BlueStacks/comments/oe2z02/comment/hwfpxte/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;context=3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">steps</a>.</p>
<p>You will need an app like X-plore to edit the Android system files in order to add our proxy and Charles root certificate. Once you've downloaded and installed the app (you can drag the .apk file directly into the emulator), press the three dots in the top right corner and press "Configuration". You'll need to set the app into "Superuser + mount writable" mode.</p>
<p>Briefly head into Charles to set up your proxy. Be sure to turn off the default "Windows proxy" switch in the Proxy tab. Then press Proxy -&gt; Proxy Settings... click both of the switches under the HTTP proxy. After that, press Help -&gt; Local IP Address and take a note of your IP.</p>
<p>Then navigate to /data/system/users/0 (this will prompt the app to allow superuser access. Press "Accept".) and open "settings_global.xml" with the app's file editor. Then add these entries anywhere into the file, making sure to change the IP address to the one given to you by Charles:</p>
<p class="_1qeIAgB0cPwnLhDF9XSiJM"><code class="_34q3PgLsx9zIU5BiSOjFoM">&lt;setting id="100" name="global_proxy_pac_url" value="" package="android" /&gt;</code><br><code class="_34q3PgLsx9zIU5BiSOjFoM">&lt;setting id="97" name="global_http_proxy_host" value="192.168.1.10" package="android" /&gt;</code><br><code class="_34q3PgLsx9zIU5BiSOjFoM">&lt;setting id="98" name="global_http_proxy_port" value="8888" package="android" /&gt;</code><br><code class="_34q3PgLsx9zIU5BiSOjFoM">&lt;setting id="99" name="global_http_proxy_exclusion_list" value="" package="android" /&gt;</code><br><code class="_34q3PgLsx9zIU5BiSOjFoM">&lt;setting id="96" name="http_proxy" value="192.168.1.10:8888" package="com.android.shell" /&gt;</code></p>
<p>Once that is done, save the file and reboot the emulator. You should start seeing HTTP(S) queries in the list, but you will not be able to see HTTPS requests yet. Turn on the SSL proxy by pressing Proxy -&gt; SSL Proxying Settings, pressing the "Enable SSL Proxying" button and adding "*" as a location.</p>
<p>Now we need to install Charles' root certificate into the emulator. To do this, save Charles' root certificate locally by pressing Help -&gt; SSL Proxying -&gt; Save Charles Root Certificate..., and then save the file somewhere locally.</p>
<p>Next, you will need to add it manually into Android's certificate store. Install OpenSSL locally and navigate to wherever you saved the certificate. Then, type these two commands, courtesy of this StackOverflow <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/44942851/install-user-certificate-via-adb/46569793#46569793" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">answer</a>:</p>
<p><code>openssl x509 -inform PEM -subject_hash_old -in cert.pem | head -1</code></p>
<p>Next, make a new text file with the name that OpenSSL gives you, with the extension .0. For example: 4a613d6b.0</p>
<p>After that, run this command:</p>
<p><code>openssl x509 -inform PEM -text -in cert.pem</code></p>
<p>And copy-paste the text into the text file we just created. Drag and drop this file into the emulator, and open X-plore again. You should find that file in /storage/emulated/0/Download. Copy that file to clipboard and paste it in /system/etc/security/cacerts.</p>
<p>Once that is done, download and install this Xposed <a href="https://github.com/ViRb3/TrustMeAlready" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">module</a>, go to the Xposed Installer -&gt; Modules and enable it. This disables SSL verification and pinning for most apps, making them trust Charles' root SSL certificate, allowing us to sniff the traffic.</p>
<p>Reboot the device, and voila! You now can sniff almost any apps' encrypted SSL traffic.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>America&#x27;s Secret Pager Giant</title>
        <author>
            <name>Maximilian Vidavsky</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://evilsaloon.com/americas-secret-pager-giant/"/>
        <id>https://evilsaloon.com/americas-secret-pager-giant/</id>
        <media:content url="https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/2/graph.PNG" medium="image" />
            <category term="pager"/>
            <category term="article"/>

        <updated>2022-07-28T17:16:16-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/2/graph.PNG" alt="" />
                    This article was originally published on HackerNoon. Early January 2022, I spontaneously bought a pager. I looked into the US pager market, and to my surprise, there were (and still are!) several companies offering pager service. After a bit of digging, I decided to sign&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://evilsaloon.com/media/posts/2/graph.PNG" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p><em>This article was originally published on <a href="https://hackernoon.com/americas-secret-pager-giant" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">HackerNoon</a>.</em></p>
<p>Early January 2022, I spontaneously bought a pager. I looked into the US pager market, and to my surprise, there were (and still are!) several companies offering pager service. After a bit of digging, I decided to sign up for <a href="https://www.mysecretaryusa.com/assured/index.htm">MySecretaryUSA’s</a> two-way pager plan.</p>
<p>While waiting for a pager to be shipped, I started to do some digging. The “Paging Coverage Area Maps” and “Send a Page” links on MySecretaryUSA’s site took me to two websites: <a href="https://www.spok.com/solutions/paging-services/check-paging-coverage/nationwide-two-way-map/">spok.com</a> and <a href="https://secure.usamobility.net/">usamobility.net</a> respectively, which immediately told me that MySecretary is a Spok/USA Mobility reseller.</p>
<p>At the time of writing, I found competing resellers, but all of them were using Spok’s network. It stands to reason that the only company offering truly nationwide paging service, as opposed to local providers that serve a single city or state, is Spok (and Spok themselves <a href="https://www.spok.com/solutions/paging-services/">claim</a> to be the nation’s largest paging network). However, in order to understand Spok as a company, I first had to understand how pagers work.</p>
<h4>Pager Recap</h4>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://cdn.hackernoon.com/images/Ukwbm9e6XigP4lRj7BnG8FH39tj2-pp93k40.jpeg" alt="My Motorola T900 Talkabout Two-Way pager" data-is-external-image="true"><figcaption>My Motorola T900 Talkabout Two-Way pager</figcaption></figure>
<p>In short, a pager is a small battery-powered device that displays messages on the go. When they were first created, they could only play a specific tone, but as technology evolved, they could play voice messages, display phone numbers and text, and eventually reply to messages. Their use among the general public significantly diminished after the popularization of cell phones, and they currently enjoy widespread use in hospitals and other medical institutions, where mobile network coverage may be spotty.</p>
<p>The pager I have is a two-way pager, meaning it can send and receive messages. My plan includes 3000 messages a month, as well as SMS messaging, a voicemail box, nationwide access, and a whole host of other features. It is worth pointing out that a pager without a plan is mostly useless to the average person. Just like a mobile phone without a SIM card can’t use any cell network (except for emergency calls), a pager needs to be activated and assigned a capcode, or a unique ID in the paging network, in order for it to work. However, hobbyists have found ways to resurrect them. If you haven’t read Dmitrii Eliuseev’s <a href="https://debugger.medium.com/howto-using-a-pager-in-the-21st-century-6a57454ecde8">article</a> about several of those ways, I highly recommend it.</p>
<p>Most modern pager plans also come with a free phone number. That phone number is how you interact with the pager: you can call it to leave a voicemail, you can text it to send a page to it, etc. When I signed up for my plan, I was asked what area code I wanted the pager to have. Since my university has courtesy phones with free local calling, this allowed me to have a voicemail box freely accessible from any phone on campus.</p>
<h4>Spok Recap</h4>
<p>Now that we know how the pager ecosystem works, let’s talk about Spok. Spok came about not because of aggressive network expansion like most modern cell carriers, but because of legacy. Part of its legacy is the largest paging network in the country, with coverage in 44 states, but how it acquired that legacy is an interesting story.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“In 2014, two powerful communication companies, USA Mobility and Amcom Software, merged into one cohesive business — and Spok was born” — <a href="https://www.spok.com/about-spok/">Spok Inc.</a></p>
</blockquote>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://cdn.hackernoon.com/images/Ukwbm9e6XigP4lRj7BnG8FH39tj2-j5a3kz4.png" alt="Spok Company History" data-is-external-image="true"><figcaption>Spok Company History</figcaption></figure>
<p>Spok’s <a href="https://www.spok.com/about-spok/spok-company-history/">history</a> technically started in 1965, one year after Motorola released their first consumer tone-only pager, the Pageboy I. However, Spok itself is relatively young, coming into existence only in 2014 via the merger of two large industry players: USA Mobility (who handle the paging/wireless side of things) and Amcom Software (a communications software company). As you can see by the flowchart above, Spok is the result of almost half a century of mergers and acquisitions.</p>
<p>Nowadays, Spok is primarily a healthcare-oriented business. Most of the promotional language on their website and Twitter account is targeted to healthcare institutions. Consumers can no longer purchase paging coverage directly from Spok, instead having to go through resellers and other third parties.</p>
<p>You might be wondering why I called Spok a “secret paging giant”. That’s because most people outside of the healthcare industry haven’t heard of them, but they have most likely visited a practice employing their products at least once. According to Spok’s 2021 Full Year earnings <a href="https://www.webcast-eqs.com/spok02172022_en/en">call</a>, every top 10 children’s hospital and top 20 adult hospital has some sort of relationship with Spok, with the oldest one being 42 years!</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://cdn.hackernoon.com/images/Ukwbm9e6XigP4lRj7BnG8FH39tj2-85b3kdk.png" alt="Spok Earnings Call graphic. Slide 11. Copyright Spok, Inc." data-is-external-image="true"><figcaption>Spok Earnings Call graphic. Slide 11. Copyright Spok, Inc.</figcaption></figure>
<p>Many of these hospitals have been using Spok’s pagers, as well as their software, for several decades, and these “Longstanding Customer Relationships” very rarely break, especially in an field as technologically inflexible as healthcare. If something works well, there’s a chance it’ll remain maintained for decades, maybe even centuries. That is Spok’s legacy, and their bread and butter going forward.</p>
<h4>CLICK HERE for Free Private Data</h4>
<p>At this point, I had spent about a week on-and-off digging into Spok. The next logical question I had was “How many customers does this company have?” The answer is not publicly available. Spok published an <a href="https://www.spok.com/resources/infographic-paging-power/">infographic</a> called “The ongoing power of paging,” where they mentioned that their network processes “more than 100 million messages/month”, but this number did not give me any clues to the total number of paging customers.</p>
<p>The solution to my problem came to me while I was looking at the “Send a Page” page. Amongst the various text boxes was the line: “<strong>Need to verify the number?</strong> <a href="https://secure.usamobility.net/message/lookup.html">CLICK HERE</a> to validate device numbers”.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://cdn.hackernoon.com/images/Ukwbm9e6XigP4lRj7BnG8FH39tj2-04c3kxn.png" alt="Spok’s “Send a Page” website" data-is-external-image="true"><figcaption>Spok’s “Send a Page” website</figcaption></figure>
<p>Upon pressing the button, you are asked to enter a number to validate, and the page makes a request to a CGI that tells you if the number is valid.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://cdn.hackernoon.com/images/Ukwbm9e6XigP4lRj7BnG8FH39tj2-prd3kmb.png" alt="" width="702" height="295" data-is-external-image="true"></figure>
<p>Great, now I had a way to check if a certain number belongs to Spok or not. At this point, all I needed to do is feed a every single possible number I could into that endpoint, and I’d not only get the total amount of customers Spok has, but I’d also get their numbers. Sounds simple, right?</p>
<p>However, I was now presented with a problem: the standard US phone number (xxx-xxx-xxxx) is 10 digits long. Going through all 10 billion possible combinations would take infeasibly long, so I needed a way to narrow down the scope of possible numbers. Thankfully, there is a way to do just that.</p>
<h4>NANPA To The Rescue</h4>
<p>NANPA is the North American Numbering Plan Administrator, the governing body responsible for administering and allocating area codes and central office codes within the North American Numbering Plan. They also publish regular reports about their activity, one of which caught my eye, the “Central Office Code Assignment Records” <a href="https://nationalnanpa.com/reports/reports_cocodes_assign.html">report</a>.</p>
<p>The report page contains a wealth of information, but the file that concerns us is “<a href="https://nationalnanpa.com/nanp1/allutlzd.zip">allutlzd.txt</a>”, a text file that lists all the assigned central office codes in the United States. These are digits 4–6 of a phone number (xxx-<strong>xxx</strong>-xxxx). Searching for “SPOK, INC” in the text file yields 0 results, but knowing their their former business name, I searched for “USA MOBILITY WIRELESS, INC” and, bingo!, I got 2336 matches.</p>
<p>Here’s a typical line from the text file:</p>
<pre><code>WI **262–231** 6630 “USA MOBILITY WIRELESS, INC.” LAKEGENEVA AS N.</code></pre>
<p>We don’t need to worry about anything except the second column, which gives us the area and central office code assigned to Spok. 2336 matches times 10000 numbers in a central office code is 23.36 million unique numbers that could potentially be active. This narrowed my range significantly, but I could not possibly go through all of these numbers sequentially.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.hackernoon.com/images/Ukwbm9e6XigP4lRj7BnG8FH39tj2-zle3kx6.png" alt="\&quot;\&quot;" data-is-external-image="true"></p>
<p>According to Insomnia, a single request to Spok’s checking CGI takes 80.5ms from start to finish, so if one were to run all the possible numbers through Spok’s checker, it would take 1.88 billion milliseconds, or around 21.8 <strong>days</strong> to complete all of the requests. Even for a one-time operation, this wait time is unacceptable. I needed to find a way to run many, many requests at the same time.</p>
<h4>AsyncIO, meet HTTPX.</h4>
<p>The first obvious step is to run these requests concurrently. Python has multiple ways to do this: multiprocessing, multithreading, and asyncio. I won’t go over the difference between these libraries, because that is out of the scope of this article, but I decided to choose asyncio. If you’re wondering what library to choose for your project, here’s an excellent Stack Overflow <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/a/52498068">answer</a> that might help.</p>
<p>Before I talk about how I automated the request process, I have to express my gratitude to Blair “r000t” Strater, who wrote the base code to quickly go through a single number range. Without his expertise, this project would have not been possible. He also suggested to use HTTPX and its HTTP connection pooling feature, which I will now briefly explain.</p>
<p>Every Python developer, no matter how experienced, has interacted with requests, probably the most legendary third-party library for the language. HTTPX is the spiritual successor to requests. Not only does it support HTTP connection pooling, but it has built-in Async support.</p>
<p>HTTP connection pooling works by establishing a single TCP connection to a server and reusing it for every subsequent request. Since establishing a single TCP connection every time one wants to make a request adds a lot of unnecessary overhead, especially when we’re making large quantities of requests every second, HTTP pooling helps us to reduce latency, CPU usage and network congestion without any additional costs.</p>
<p>With r000t’s help, I now had a working scraper that could submit hundreds of numbers a second to Spok’s CGI. Over the course of a few days (more on why this is significant much later in the article), I ran my script and gathered exactly <strong>478,729</strong> numbers. This amounts to a utilization of their NANPA assignments of about 2.05%. That’s a lot of room for future expansion!</p>
<h4>Gathering Data</h4>
<p>Now that I had all these numbers, it should be easy to correlate them to their respective ZIP codes, since central office codes are assigned to a geographical region, right</p>
<p>Wrong again. I had naively assumed that NANPA would provide that data publicly. Let’s look at NANPA’s website <a href="https://www.nationalnanpa.com/guide/guide.html">guide</a>, where they claim:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Here are some things you will <strong>NOT</strong> find on this site: […] Location of an area code/prefix. Applicants for prefix assignments are not required to disclose to NANPA the “localities” that the prefix assignments will serve. Thus NANPA does not have this information.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The only location datum that NANPA does provide is “rate center”, which is only tangentially related to geography, and can be incredibly confusing to correlate to a real location. For example, look at the line:</p>
<pre><code>CA 213–350 6630 “USA MOBILITY WIRELESS, INC.” **LSAN DA 01** AS N\n</code></pre>
<p>What does “LSAN DA 01” even mean? It’s related to Los Angeles somehow, but doesn’t give us any clues in regards to its zip code. However, in that same guide, NANPA says:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“information on the correspondence between zip codes and area codes is available through various sources on the web. Find them by using a search engine.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And after exactly one Google query, I stumbled upon area-codes.com, whose easily-abusable website allowed me to correlate each central office code to a ZIP code. Two hours of automated Selenium queries later, I had a text file with all of the ZIP codes used by Spok. I combined all of them, counted all of the numbers in that zip code, and via <a href="https://simplemaps.com/data/us-zips">Simplemaps’ US Zips Database</a>, I now had all the states, cities, and counties Spok had customers in.</p>
<h4>Except, It’s Never Really That Simple…</h4>
<p>Firstly, I have to mention that just because these numbers belong to Spok, it doesn’t mean that they are “consumer” paging customers. One of Spok’s products is a turn-key contact center, and their main line of business is enterprise-level healthcare paging, which means a number could be a hospital’s main customer service line, or a doctor’s phone number.</p>
<p>Secondly, there is a degree of fallibility in my results. I am using ZIP codes as a proxy for location. Not only can area-codes.com’s database be inaccurate, but so can Simplemaps’. I am converting from central office code to ZIP, and then again to city/county/state. Any error at any step could give false results.</p>
<p>Let’s take a look at the State, County, and City graphs for the data I gathered:</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://cdn.hackernoon.com/images/Ukwbm9e6XigP4lRj7BnG8FH39tj2-hof3ktg.png" alt="Total numbers of customers by US state. Visualization by Plotly" data-is-external-image="true"><figcaption>
<div class="image-container undefined">
<p class="image-caption">Total numbers of customers by US state. Visualization by Plotly</p>
</div>
</figcaption></figure>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://cdn.hackernoon.com/images/Ukwbm9e6XigP4lRj7BnG8FH39tj2-f4g3k8p.png" alt="Total numbers of customers by US county. Visualization by Plotly" data-is-external-image="true"><figcaption>Total numbers of customers by US county. Visualization by Plotly</figcaption></figure>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://cdn.hackernoon.com/images/Ukwbm9e6XigP4lRj7BnG8FH39tj2-u5h3kuy.png" alt="Total numbers of customers by US city" data-is-external-image="true"><figcaption>Total numbers of customers by US city</figcaption></figure>
<p>Three things jumped out at me immediately after I finished compiling these data:</p>
<ol>
<li>479 thousand numbers isn’t all that much. Even if we assume all of these are paging customers, and do not contain any call center or service numbers (modems for the paging network, etc.), that’s, for example, 7.3 times less than the number of Facebook Messenger users in Costa Rica (according to <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1071951/number-users-messenger-costa-rica/">Statista</a>)</li>
<li>The data are extraordinarily geographically spread, and customer counts rapidly drop off after the top 100 cities. The top 10 cities only make up 37.4% of all customers, but the top 100 cities make up 90.1% of all customers (out of a total of 501)</li>
<li>I’m not particularly knowledgeable in US geography, since I’m an international student here, but I’ve never heard of Grand Prairie, TX before in my life. Why does that one city have so many pager numbers?</li>
</ol>
<h4>The Grand Prairie Anomaly</h4>
<p>Let’s explore the Grand Prairie anomaly. The first thing I did was Google what “Grand Prairie” even is. Turns out it’s a city in the Fort Worth-Dallas twin city area with a population of about 194 thousand people (according to the 2020 US Census).</p>
<p>The second thing I did was go back to my raw data and sum up all the numbers with the “GRANDPRARI” rate center, since I assumed that numbers in that area won’t be assigned to any other rate center. To my surprise, I ended up with more numbers than in my city graph! 23973 as opposed to 23617 ZIP-geocoded numbers. This immediately tells us two things: either pagers have a 12.4% penetration in such a small city, or there’s another factor at play.</p>
<p>A clue could be hiding on Spok’s “Contact us” <a href="https://www.spok.com/contact-us/">page</a>. They claim to have two locations in the US: one in Alexandria, VA, another in Plano, TX. Looking at FCC filings (file number <a href="https://licensing.fcc.gov/cgi-bin/ws.exe/prod/ib/forms/reports/swr031b.hts?q_set=V_SITE_ANTENNA_FREQ.file_numberC/File+Number/%3D/SESRWL2017071400761&amp;prepare=&amp;column=V_SITE_ANTENNA_FREQ.file_numberC/File+Number">SESRWL2017071400761</a>), they seem to have a ground satellite station at their address at 3000 Technology Drive, as seen on Google Maps satellite view.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://cdn.hackernoon.com/images/Ukwbm9e6XigP4lRj7BnG8FH39tj2-mci3klg.png" alt="Imagery ©2022 Maxar Technologies, Map data ©2022 Google" data-is-external-image="true"><figcaption>
<div class="image-container undefined">
<p class="image-caption">Imagery ©2022 Maxar Technologies, Map data ©2022 Google</p>
</div>
</figcaption></figure>
<p>Plano is located in the Fort Worth-Dallas area just like Grand Prairie, but this alone doesn’t explain why so many numbers are located in that area. This could be anything from a cost saving measure (Grand Prairie is its own distinct rate center) to an amassing of corporate numbers for testing. I wish I had a more satisfying answer for this anomaly, but unless Spok clarifies the situation, we’ll never truly know.</p>
<h4>Yet More Anomalies</h4>
<p>The more I kept looking at the data, the more I was amazed by the uniqueness of this dataset:</p>
<ul>
<li>Grand Prairie, TX, number 135 (!) city in the US by population, is number 2 (!!) on my list</li>
<li>Los Angeles, CA, number 2 by population, is on spot 23 (!!!)</li>
<li>Milwaukee, WI, number 30 by population, is on spot 4</li>
<li>Pittsburgh, PA, number 68 by population, is on spot 5</li>
<li>Phoenix, AZ, number 5 by population, is on spot 19</li>
</ul>
<p>(population data taken from <a href="https://worldpopulationreview.com/us-cities">World Population Review</a>)</p>
<p>Even the cities with the most numbers occupy only a fraction of the total percentage of numbers. Chicago, IL, number one on my list, takes up only 5.79% of the dataset. Out of 501 cities:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Only the top 10 have more than 10,000 numbers</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Only the top 83 have more than 1,000 numbers</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Only the top 238 have more than 100 numbers</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Only the top 359 have more than 10 numbers</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>There are 38 cities with only 1 number</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>And a single city with 0 numbers: Woodbury Heights, NJ</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>My favorite anomaly probably has to be Arkansas. Arkansas doesn’t have any pager towers, the only service that it gets is bleed-over from Memphis across state lines (see if you can spot it on the following <a href="http://cloud.spok.com/coverage/NationwideTwo-way/AR.pdf">map</a> without my red highlight).</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://cdn.hackernoon.com/images/Ukwbm9e6XigP4lRj7BnG8FH39tj2-v2j3kk4.png" alt="Arkansas Two-Way Pager Coverage Map. Copyright Spok, Inc" data-is-external-image="true"><figcaption>Arkansas Two-Way Pager Coverage Map. Copyright Spok, Inc</figcaption></figure>
<p>Despite this, in my dataset is a single number from Fort Smith, AR, a town with a population of about 87 thousand (according to the 2020 US Census), on the complete opposite side of the state border. Not only that, but it is the <strong>only</strong> Arkansas number in my dataset. I don’t think I can put into words the astonishment I felt when I discovered this.</p>
<p>This, however, is the perfect time for me to reiterate that a number doesn’t necessarily mean a pager is active in that area. The most likely explanation I have is that a customer from the Memphis area frequently called into Fort Smith or was stationed there, so it would be more convenient for them to acquire a Fort Smith number.</p>
<h4>Conclusion</h4>
<p>Spok is a fascinating company. They have managed to survive the death of consumer paging by clinging onto healthcare institutions, and yet they still offer paging service all across the country. Their legacy shows us how ancient tech can stick around long after it has been discontinued by manufacturers.</p>
<p>A careful reader might have started wondering how I was able to gather so much data from Spok in such a short amount of time. The answer is simple: the CGI I used didn’t employ any authentication, has no rate limits, and doesn’t employ any header checking. That CGI is a relic of an older, naiver time, when privacy was simply not thought of when it came to user interfaces. I was easily able to send 100 requests a second to it, and it only started to “choke” at around 250.</p>
<p>Nowadays, no such API (we don’t even use CGI’s anymore) would make it into production. Spok’s “Send a Page” website is a time capsule that shows us the pitfalls of legacy tech. Sure, you get to keep all of your old customers, but if you don’t maintain or proactively work to secure your old interfaces, some script kiddie (or, even worse, a competitor) might just show up and scrape all of your data.</p>
<p>I am choosing to open source the processed dataset for future researchers to play with (the raw numbers, however, will not be published due to ethical and privacy reasons):</p>
<p><a href="https:/github.com/evilsaloon/spok-dataset">https://github.com/evilsaloon/spok-dataset</a>. I hope it is of some use.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Hello, World!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Maximilian Vidavsky</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://evilsaloon.com/hello-world/"/>
        <id>https://evilsaloon.com/hello-world/</id>

        <updated>2022-07-28T17:16:10-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Hello, world! Welcome to my personal blog. I'm a sophomore at Penn State, studying Computer Science at the University Park campus. I'm also the president of the Slavic Club. I speak English and Russian fluently, and I'm pretty comfortable with Python. I'm also currently learning&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Hello, world! Welcome to my personal blog. I'm a sophomore at Penn State, studying Computer Science at the University Park campus. I'm also the president of the <a href="https://orgcentral.psu.edu/organization/slavicclub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Slavic Club</a>. I speak English and Russian fluently, and I'm pretty comfortable with Python. I'm also currently learning Java.</p>
<p>This blog will mostly be about the things I'm interested in: fintech, obsolete tech like pagers, and everything else in between! I enjoy writing about obscure topics and sharing them with a wider audience. I try to write in a way that is accessible to the average person.</p>
<p>If you have any feedback, feel free to shoot me a <a href="https://twitter.com/evilsaloon" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter DM</a> or an <a href="mailto:max@evilsaloon.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">e-mail</a>. I'll try to get back to you as soon as I can.</p>
<p>Enjoy the blog!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
